Guide to the Records of Religious Educational Institutions
Yale University Divinity School Library
Records of Religious Educational Institutions
1808-1974
RG 33
Yale University Divinity School Library
23
(47 boxes)
Record Group 33 is an open collection composed primarily of printed material from the institutions represented. This collection includes records from religious educational institutions in the United States and Canada, dating from 1808 to 1974.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Material gathered from various sources.
Biographical / Historical
This collection contains material dating from 1808 to 1974. The documentation was not systematically collected, but rather represents materials that have come to the library by various means.
Scope and Contents
Record Group No. 33 is arranged alphabetically by the name of the institution. The collection includes records from religious educational institutions in the United States and Canada, dating from 1808 to 1974. The bulk of the material in this collection is made up of journals, bulletins, catalogues and alumni materials, dating primarily from the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries. The institutions are arranged alphabetically with name changes noted when pertinent. The material for each institution is arranged chronologically except where the quantity of material warrants a more detailed arrangement. A small portion of the collection is in German and Swedish.
Arrangement
The material is arranged Alphabetically by the name of the institution.
Christian education; Theology -- Study and teaching
- Alphabetical arrangement of institutions, Series I
  - Allegheny Theological Seminary, PA
    - General, 1860, 1883 (Box 1)
  - Alliance Theological Seminary, NY
    - General, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Alton Theological Seminary, IL
    - General, 1854 (Box 1)
  - Andover Theological Seminary, MA
    - Anniversary Programs, 1825-1904 (Box 2)
    - Catalogues, 1810-1889 (Box 2)
    - Constitutions and Laws, 1808-1857 (Box 3)
    - Controversies, 1886-1887 (Box 3)
    - Courses of Study, 1819-1906 (Box 4)
    - Necrology, 1858-1906 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1819-1906 (Box 4)
    - Bulletins, 1882-1892 (Box 5)
  - Andover Newton Theological School, MA
    - General, 1951 (Box 5)
    - Bulletins, 1938-1956 (Box 5)
    - Bulletins, 1957-1960 (Box 6)
  - Asbury Theological Seminary, KY
    - General, 1963-1967 (Box 1)
  - Ashland Theological Seminary, OH
    - General, 1968-1974 (Box 1)
  - Auburn Theological Seminary, NY
    - Catalogues, 1842-1931 (Box 7)
    - Auburn Seminary Review, 1898 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1825-1926 (Box 7)
  - Augustana Theological Seminary, IL
    - Review (after 1962 see Lutheran School of Theology), 1949-1962 (Box 6)
  - Austin Presbyterian Theological Seminary, TX
    - General, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Bangor Theological Seminary, ME
    - Catalogues, 1827-1888 (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous, 1830-1916 (Box 8)
  - Berkeley Divinity School, CT
    - Catalogues, 1856-1970 (Box 9)
    - Alumni Newsletters, 1936-1971 (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous, 1879-1971, n.d. (Box 9)
    - Bulletins, 1909-1967 (Box 10)
  - Bethany Biblical Seminary, Chicago, IL
    - Bulletins, 1941-1948 (Box 11)
  - Bethany Institute, NY
    - General, 1880 (Box 11)
  - Bethel Seminary, MN
    - Journals, 1965-1967 (Box 11)
  - Bible Institute of Los Angeles, CA
    - General, 1918 (Box 11)
  - Bible Normal College, MA
    - General, 1898 (Box 11)
  - Bishop Payne Divinity School, VA
    - General, 1908 (Box 11)
  - Boston School for the Ministry, MA
    - General, 1868 (Box 11)
  - Boston Theological Seminary, see Boston University,School of Theology
  - Boston University, School of Theology, MA (prior to 1872 known as Boston Theological Seminary)
    - General, 1868-1905 (Box 11)
  - Campbell Institute, AR
    - General, 1967 (Box 12)
  - Catholic University of America, DC
    - General, 1953 (Box 12)
  - Cedarville College, OH
    - General, 1921 (Box 12)
  - Central Baptist Theological Seminary, KS
    - General, 1946, n.d. (Box 12)
  - Central Theological Seminary, OH
    - General, 1924-1932 (Box 12)
  - Chautauqua School of Theology, NY
    - General, 1883 (Box 12)
  - Chicago Theological Seminary, IL
    - Catalogues, 1859-1888 (Box 13)
    - Catalogues, 1933-1935 (Box 13)
    - Charters and Constitutions, 1855-1875 (Box 13)
    - Minutes of Triennial Conventions, 1864-1900 (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 1861, 1879-1932 (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 1934, 1936 (Box 13)
    - Quarterly, 1901-1907 (Box 13)
    - Quarterly, 1934-1937 (Box 13)
    - Register, 1930-1937 (Box 47)
  - Christian Biblical Institute, NY
    - General, 1894 (Box 1)
  - Church Divinity School of the Pacific, CA
    - General, 1939-1951 (Box 47)
  - Claremont Associated Colleges, CA
    - General, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Colgate Theological Seminary, NY
    - General, 1927 (Box 1)
  - Colgate-Rochester Divinity School, NY
    - General, 1930-1931, 1968 (Box 1)
  - College of the Bible, KY (now Lexington Theological Seminary)
    - Exponent Monthly Magazine, 1886 (Box 14)
    - Bulletins, 1918-1965 (Box 14)
  - Columbia College, NY
    - General, 1892, 1898 (Box 1)
  - Columbia Theological Seminary, SC
    - General, 1912-1957 (Box 1)
  - Crozer Theological Seminary, PA
    - General, 1948, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Dallas Theological Seminary, TX
    - General, 1960 (Box 15)
  - Danville Theological Seminary, KY
    - General, 1854-1895 (Box 15)
  - Divinity School of the Protestant Episcopal Church in Philadelphia, PA
    - General, 1864-1892 (Box 15)
  - Divinity School of the Univ. of Chicago, IL
    - General, 1926-1939, n.d. (Box 15)
  - Drew Theological Seminary, NJ
    - General, 1867-1895 (Box 15)
  - Dubuque Theological Seminary, IA
    - General, 1947-1950, 1968 (Box 15)
  - Duke Divinity School, NC (formerly known as the Duke School of Religion)
    - Bulletins, 1939-1952 (Box 15)
    - Bulletins, 1953-1963 (Box 16)
  - East Maine Conference Seminary, ME
    - General, 1886 (Box 16)
  - Eden Theological Seminary, MO
    - General, 1925 (Box 16)
    - Bulletin, 1962-1964 (Box 16)
  - Elmhurst College, IL
    - General, 1918 (Box 16)
  - Episcopal Theological School, MA
    - Catalogues, 1868-1884 (Box 16)
    - Bulletins, 1924-1936 (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous, 1867-1924, 1967 (Box 16)
  - Evangelical Lutheran Missionary Institute, PA
    - General, 1869-1870 (Box 16)
  - Evangelical Lutheran Synod of Wisconsin Theological Seminary
    - General, 1910 (Box 17)
  - Garrett Biblical Institute, IL (Now Garrett Theological Seminary)
    - Catalogues, 1857-1886 (Box 17)
    - Catalogues and Bulletins, 1915-1920 (Box 17)
    - Catalogues and Bulletins, 1920-1924 (Box 18)
    - The Garrett Tower, 1965 (Box 18)
  - General Theological Library, NY
    - General, 1870 (Box 18)
  - General Theological Seminary of the Protestant Episcopal Church in the U.S., NY
    - General, 1859 (Box 47)
  - General Theological Seminary, NY
    - Associate Alumni, 1840-1887 (Box 18)
    - Standing Committee Reports, 1882-1904 (Box 18)
    - Catalogues, 1834-1884 (Box 19)
    - Controversies, 1844-1892 (Box 19)
    - Constitutions and Statutes, 1822-1900, n.d. (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous, 1829-1942 (Box 20)
    - Board of Trustees: Documents, 1847-1943 (Box 20)
    - BT: Annual Meeting, 1824-1887 (Box 20)
    - BT: Proceedings (bound volumes), 1821-1865 (Box 21)
    - BT: Proceedings (bound volumes), 1866-1884 (Box 22)
  - George Mercer, Jr. Memorial School of Theology, NY
    - General, 1966 (Box 47)
  - German Evangelical Lutheran Church Teaching Institutions
    - General, 1874-1894 (Box 22)
  - German Theological School of Newark, NJ
    - General, 1872-1900 (Box 22)
  - Gilmanton Theological Seminary, NH
    - General, 1839 (Box 22)
  - Golden Gate Baptist Theological Seminary, CA
    - General, 1965 (Box 22)
  - Gordon Review, MA
    - General, 1957-1964 (Box 22)
  - Hamilton Literary and Theological Institution, NY
    - General, 1834-1842 (Box 22)
  - Hamma Divinity School, OH
    - General, 1961 (Box 22)
  - Hartford Seminary, CT (previously known as the Theological Institute of Connecticut, and Hartford Theological Seminary)
    - Miscellaneous, 1842-1879, n.d. (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous, 1880-1889 (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous, 1890-1941 (Box 23)
    - Bulletin, 1958-1959 (Box 23)
    - Quarterly, 1960-1965 (Box 23)
    - Quarterly, 1966-1968 (Box 24)
  - Hartwick Seminary, NY
    - General, 1873 (Box 24)
  - Harvard Divinity School, MA
    - Miscellaneous, 1824, n.d. (Box 24)
    - Catalogues, 1898-1910 (Box 24)
    - Catalogue, 1920 (Box 25)
    - Bulletins, 1935-1938 (Box 25)
    - Bulletins, 1940-1949 (Box 25)
    - Bulletins, 1950-1956 (Box 25)
    - Bulletins, 1956-1959 (Box 26)
    - HDS: Bulletins, 1960-1969 (Box 26)
  - Holy Cross, College of the, MA
    - General, 1920 (Box 26)
  - House of the Evangelists, NY
    - General, 1873 (Box 26)
  - Howard University School of Religion, Washington, D.C.
    - General, 1921, 1928 (Box 26)
  - Immanuel Deaconess Institute, NE
    - General, 1901 (Box 26)
  - Ingham University, NY
    - General, 1858-1884 (Box 26)
  - Jarvis Hall, CO
    - General, 1880 (Box 26)
  - Jewish Institute of Religion
    - General, 1963 (Box 26)
  - Jubilee College, IL
    - General, 1843 (Box 26)
  - Kenyon College, OH
    - Miscellaneous, 1827-1848 (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous, 1855-1880 (Box 27)
  - Knox College, IL
    - General, 1859 (Box 27)
  - Lane Theological Seminary, OH
    - Annual Reports, 1834-1835, 1871 (Box 27)
    - Catalogues, 1834-1899 (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous, 1832-1894, n.d. (Box 27)
  - Lexington Theological Seminary
    - see College of the Bible
  - Lutheran School of Theology, IL
    - The Seminary Review (prior to 1962 see Augustana Theological Seminary), 1962-1966 (Box 28)
  - Lutheran Theological Seminary, Gettysburg, PA
    - Bulletins, 1963-1972 (Box 28)
  - Lutheran Theological Seminary, Philadelphia, PA
    - General, 1924-1928 (Box 29)
  - McMaster Divinity College, Ontario
    - General, 1937, 1967-1971 (Box 29)
  - Meadville Theological School, PA
    - Catalogues, 1856-1890 (Box 29)
    - Bulletins, 1906-1910 (Box 29)
    - Bulletins, 1911-1933 (Box 29)
  - Merom Institute, IN-IL
    - General, 1942 (Box 30)
  - Methodist General Biblical Institute, NH
    - General, 1853-1863 (Box 30)
  - Methodist Theological School in Ohio
    - General, 1962-1973 (Box 31)
  - Moody Bible Institute of Chicago, IL
    - General, 1894-1921, n.d. (Box 31)
  - Mount Hermon, Summer School for Bible Study, MA
    - General, 1886 (Box 31)
  - Nashotah Theological Seminary, WI
    - General, 1849-1882 (Box 31)
  - National Academy of Theology, NY
    - General, 1889 (Box 31)
  - New Brunswick Theological Seminary, NJ
    - General, 1934 (Box 31)
  - New Hampton Institution, NH
    - General, 1851-1868 (Box 31)
  - New York Conference Seminary, NY
    - General, 1853 (Box 31)
  - New York Theological Seminary, NY
    - General, 1838-1841 (Box 31)
    - General, 1838-1841 (Box 31)
  - New York Training School for Deaconnesses, NY
    - General, 1891 (Box 31)
  - Newton Theological Institution, MA
    - Catalogues, 1831-1881 (Box 32)
    - Miscellaneous, 1830, 1866 (Box 32)
  - Northfield Seminary, MA
    - General, n.d. (Box 32)
  - Northwestern Lutheran Theological Seminary, MN
    - General, 1951-1955 (Box 32)
  - Oberlin Theological Seminary, OH
    - General, 1871-1891, n.d. (Box 32)
  - Otterbein College, OH
    - General, 1939 (Box 32)
  - Pacific School of Religion, CA
    - General, 1951 (Box 32)
  - Pacific Theological Seminary, CA
    - General, 1867-1908 (Box 32)
  - Phillips Academy, MA
    - General, 1854, 1892, n.d. (Box 32)
  - Princeton Theological Seminary, NJ
    - Board of Directors' Reports, 1816-1822 (Box 32)
    - Miscellaneous, 1816-1875, n.d. (Box 32)
    - Catalogues, 1829-1894 (Box 33)
    - Necrological Reports, 1857 (Box 33)
  - Providence Conference Seminary, RI
    - General, 1857 (Box 34)
  - Queen's Theological Seminary, Ontario
    - General, 1913-1936 (Box 34)
  - Richmond Theological Seminary, VA (prior to 1886, known as the Richmond Institute)
    - General, 1885-1890 (Box 34)
  - Rochester Theological Seminary, NY
    - General, 1918-1928 (Box 34)
    - Catalogues, 1853-1878 (Box 34)
  - St. Joseph's Seminary, NY
    - General, 1961-1963 (Box 47)
  - St. Stephen's Normal and Theological School, VA
    - General, 1882-1883 (Box 34)
  - School for Christian Workers, MA
    - General, 1885-1894 (Box 35)
  - Seabury Divinity School, MN
    - General, 1870-1925 (Box 35)
  - Shaw University, NC
    - General, 1940 (Box 35)
  - Sloan's Seminary, CT
    - General, 1854 (Box 35)
  - Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary, NC
    - The Outlook, 1961-1971 (Box 35)
  - Southern Baptist Theological Seminary, SC
    - General, 1868-1884 (Box 35)
  - Southern Seminary Foundation, TN
    - General, n.d. (Box 35)
  - Springfield College, MA
    - General, 1923 (Box 47)
  - Theological Institute of Connecticut
    - see Hartford Seminary
  - Theological Seminaries of the Methodist Episcopal Church
    - General, 1924 (Box 35)
  - Theological Seminary, Andover, MA
    - General, 1827, 1831, 1846 (Box 47)
  - Theological Seminary of the Dutch Reformed Church
    - see: Theological Seminary of the Reformed Church of America
  - Theological Seminary of the Evangelical Lutheran Church, PA and IL
    - Bulletin, 1930-1937 (Box 35)
    - Bulletin, 1938-1950 (Box 36)
    - Bulletin, 1951-1957 (Box 37)
  - Theological Seminary of the Protestant Episcopal Church, VA
    - General, 1841-1886 (Box 37)
  - Theological Seminary of the Reformed Church of America, NJ (formerly Dutch Reformed)
    - General, 1894 (Box 37)
  - Theological Seminary of the Reformed Episcopal Church, PA
    - General, 1894 (Box 38)
  - Union Theological Seminary, NY
    - Alumni Records, 1884-1936 (Box 38)
    - Catalogues, 1840-1899 (Box 38)
    - Constitutions and By-Laws, 1839-1875 (Box 38)
    - Miscellaneous, 1891-1945, n.d. (Box 39)
    - The Seminary Student, 1892-1893 (Box 39)
    - The Union Review, 1940-1944 (Box 39)
  - Union Theological Seminary, VA
    - Miscellaneous, 1859-1930 (Box 39)
    - Union Seminary Magazine, 1889-1912 (Box 39)
    - Union Seminary Review, 1924-1933 (Box 40)
    - Union Seminary Review, 1934-1940 (Box 41)
    - Affirmation, 1966-1969 (Box 41)
  - United Presbyterian Theological Seminary, OH
    - General, 1860, 1894 (Box 41)
  - United Theological College, Montreal
    - General, 1939 (Box 41)
  - United Theological Seminary, OH
    - General, 1950-1969 (Box 42)
  - University of the South, TN
    - General, 1963 (Box 47)
  - University of Trinity College, Toronto
    - General, 1898-1947 (Box 42)
  - Vanderbilt Divinity School, TN
    - General, 1963-1965 (Box 42)
  - Vermont Episcopal Insitute, VT
    - General, 1838 (Box 42)
  - Virginia Baptist Seminary, VA
    - General, n.d. (Box 42)
  - Virginia Theological Seminary, VA
    - The Seminarian, 1879-1882 (Box 42)
    - The Seminarian, 1883-1890, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Warwick Woodlands, NY
    - General, 1881 (Box 43)
  - Washington College, CT
    - General, 1835 (Box 43)
  - Washington County Seminary, NY
    - General, 1857 (Box 43)
  - Wayland Seminary, DC
    - General, 1887 (Box 43)
  - Wesleyan Theological College, Montreal
    - General, 1891-1923 (Box 43)
  - Wesleyan University, CT
    - General, n.d. (Box 43)
  - West Virginia Wesleyan College, WV
    - General, 1961-1969 (Box 44)
  - Western Baptist Theological Institute, KY
    - General, 1843 (Box 44)
  - Western Reserve College, OH
    - General, 1873 (Box 44)
  - Western Seminary, MI
    - Bulletin, 1847-1955 (Box 44)
  - Western Theological Seminary, PA
    - General, 1845-1898 (Box 44)
    - Bulletin, 1910-1920 (Box 45)
    - Bulletin, 1921-1931 (Box 46)
  - Williston Seminary, MA
    - General, 1849, 1854 (Box 46)
  - Wittenburg College, OH
    - General, 1925-1926 (Box 46)